one of the other big ones that I came up
with in the very beginning that I love
the idea of and haven't talked about yet
is a history website and how I
envisioned that is very much like a
Google map but besides just being
zoomable in space
it is also zoomable in time so you're
able to go from evolutionary time to
current historical time and zoom in and
out of places so I could see the whole
African continent and how the borders
have changed how the tribes used to it
used to be there and where their
territories were get the information for
what tribes for doing what and what
happened in North America before
settlers came here I just having access
to all that information but in a way
that's very visual and very I mean I see
different museums from all over the
world being able to post pictures of
their artifacts and their stuff and so
you can go and see it in person or you
could have this like and what does that
mean and how do how do we know that
that's true how do we know that it's
dated at that date how do we like this
tool how do we know that was used for
that and sometimes we don't it's
complete speculation but that's what
history is and the more were able to
discuss it and see it and it can be
different sides its history is
definitely not a black and white even
science that's very scientific is it
black and white you can have different
studies showing contradicting happens
all the time contradicting outcomes and
so history can be the same or like one
side says this is what happens well
where's the evidence the other side says
this is what happens okay well where is
the evidence and both can be present and
being able to follow nouns through
histories so like people places things
so being able to see okay when Einstein
was coming up with the theory of
relativity what else was going on in the
world and well Darwin was having his
journey what was Wallace doing who if
you don't know is the other person who
came up with the UM natural selection
theory at the same time this Darwin
be able to see more of the history that
isn't white male straight colonizing
history because that's what we're that
will be there too but it's a piece of it
it's not all of it and it's a piece that
like all the other people all the other
continents all the other people that
weren't conquered by Britain are really
important and I would like to know what
different classes what different classes
went through I don't care what a king
and queen necessarily his lifestyle was
I want to know what the people at the
bottom of that hierarchy had lives that
we're like and I mean I also want to at
the king cleaner because I think we me
living in Vancouver below the poverty
line actually lives a much better life
than a king or queen 150 years ago just
based on technology and the people
around me so a zoomable historical map
where you're able to see everything
everything on a single book that's not
too much right okay so that is this is
what my longer ones that's kind of funny
I'm used to getting them under five
minutes to begin with was heart and now
of like wow three minutes that's long
the history up thank you